Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an advanced level lesson for you guys all about
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节高级课程，内容全是关于
food.
食物。
What kind of food are we talking about today, Marco?
我们今天在聊什么食物呢，Marco？
Today we're talking about cheese.
今天我们聊的是奶酪。
So there's so many different types of cheese, so many varieties.
所以奶酪有很多不同的种类，品种繁多。
So we're going to take a look at these varieties.
所以我们要来看看这些品种。
You may know them or not.
你可能认识它们，也可能不认识。
But we're also going to take a look at the pronunciation because most of them are either
但我们还会关注发音，因为大多数奶酪名字要么是
Italian or French.
意大利语或法语。
So how do you pronounce these in maybe in American English?
那么，在美式英语里这些词怎么发音呢？
Good question.
好问题。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a moment to talk
让我们第一次听一下对话，稍后我们会回来继续聊
about the wonderful world of cheese.
奶酪的奇妙世界。
Hello everyone.
大家好。
My name is Lori and I want to welcome you to this course.
我是Lori，欢迎你们来参加这门课程。
We will learn all about one of the oldest yet most delicious foods on this planet, cheese.
我们将全面了解地球上最古老但最美味的食物之一——奶酪。
Let's get started.
我们开始吧。
Cheese is usually categorized into four types, soft, semi-soft, semi-hard, and hard.
奶酪通常分为四种类型：软质、半软质、半硬质和硬质。
The designation refers to the amount of moisture in the cheese which directly affects its texture.
这个分类指的是奶酪中的水分含量，直接影响其质地。
Making cheese is an ancient practice dating back thousands of years and the home cheese
制作奶酪是一种古老的做法，可以追溯到几千年前，家庭奶酪
maker can usually find recipes for cheese that fall into any of the four categories.
制作者通常能找到属于这四类中任何一类的奶酪食谱。
Soft cheese includes cottage cheese, cream cheese, ricotta, brie, blue, roquefort, mozzarella,
软质奶酪包括白软干酪、奶油奶酪、里科塔奶酪、布里奶酪、蓝纹奶酪、罗克福奶酪、马苏里拉奶酪、
muenster, and similar cheeses.
门斯特奶酪以及类似奶酪。
These cheeses generally pair well with fruit or meats and can be used as breakfast cheeses
这些奶酪通常与水果或肉类搭配得很好，可以用作早餐奶酪
in an omelet or as pasta fillings.
做煎蛋卷或作为意大利面馅料。
They are usually mildly flavored and very high in moisture.
它们通常味道温和，水分含量很高。
American, Colby, Kojak, and similar cheeses are in the semi-soft category.
美式奶酪、科尔比奶酪、科杰克奶酪以及类似奶酪属于半软质类别。
These are slightly stronger in flavor and cover a wide range of uses.
这些奶酪味道稍浓，用途广泛。
Kojak cheese, a blend of Colby and Monterey Jack, is one of the most popular.
科杰克奶酪是科尔比奶酪和蒙特雷杰克奶酪的混合，是最受欢迎的之一。
This allows the sharper flavor of the Colby to be combined with the milder Jack cheese
这使得科尔比奶酪更浓烈的味道与更温和的杰克奶酪相结合，
and also melts better than plain Colby.
而且比纯科尔比奶酪更容易融化。
Grilled cheese sandwiches often use American cheese and Mexican cheeses such as asadero
烤奶酪三明治通常使用美式奶酪，而墨西哥奶酪如阿萨德罗奶酪
and queso fresco are becoming more popular.
和克索弗雷斯科奶酪正变得越来越受欢迎。
Hard cheeses include parmesan, romano, asiago, swiss, gruyere, and others.
硬质奶酪包括帕尔马干酪、罗马诺干酪、阿西亚戈干酪、瑞士干酪、格鲁耶尔干酪等。
Parmesan and romano are most familiar as the grated powder used to top spaghetti, but they
帕尔马干酪和罗马诺干酪最熟悉的是作为撒在意大利面上的粉末，但它们
are also used as a companion mince for fruit, wine, nuts, and other appetizer items.
也用作水果、葡萄酒、坚果和其他开胃菜的搭配。
Swiss is a popular sandwich cheese and melts well, unlike some other hard cheeses.
瑞士干酪是一种受欢迎的三明治奶酪，融化效果好，不像其他一些硬质奶酪。
Alright we're back, so obviously this is a very interesting lesson because it also gives
好了，我们回来了，显然这是一节非常有趣的课程，因为它也让我们
us an insight on how cheeses are categorized.
了解了奶酪是如何分类的。
I personally did not know that you had all these categories of cheeses.
我个人之前不知道奶酪有这么多类别。
Starting out with the soft cheeses.
从软质奶酪开始。
That's right, so basically they're broken into these soft, semi-soft, semi-hard, and
没错，所以基本上它们被分为软质、半软质、半硬质和
hard categories.
硬质这几类。
The soft cheeses are the ones that are actually, you know, you could touch them and they're
软质奶酪就是那些，你知道，你可以摸它们，它们很
soft, they kind of move under your finger.
软，手指按上去会动。
And the famous ones I think are cottage cheese, which is almost like yogurt.
我觉得有名的有白软干酪，它几乎像酸奶一样。
Yeah, and cream cheese.
是的，还有奶油奶酪。
And cream cheese as well.
还有奶油奶酪。
But also ricotta, and brie, and roquefort, and mozzarella.
但也有里科塔奶酪、布里奶酪、罗克福奶酪和马苏里拉奶酪。
So for example, these cheeses, they're usually, well they're obviously very soft cheeses.
所以例如，这些奶酪，它们通常，嗯，显然是非常软的奶酪。
Do you say cheeses or cheese, or chees-eye?
你是说cheeses还是cheese，还是chees-eye？
Yeah we just say cheese normally, or different kinds of cheese, so in that case you make
嗯，我们通常就说cheese，或者different kinds of cheese，所以在这种情况下，你用
the plural kinds of cheese.
复数形式kinds of cheese。
Types of cheese.
Types of cheese。
So these kinds of cheese, they are recommended, or they say that they pair well with fruits
所以这些种类的奶酪，它们被推荐，或者说它们与水果
or meat.
或肉类搭配得很好。
So when we talk about pairing a cheese with fruits, or pairing a cheese with wine, what
所以当我们说把奶酪和水果搭配，或者把奶酪和葡萄酒搭配，我们
are we saying there?
在说什么呢？
In that case we're saying that it's best to eat with certain kinds of food.
在这种情况下，我们说的是最好与某些食物一起吃。
So you can say, I would recommend pairing this red wine with lamb.
所以你可以说，我推荐把这种红酒和羊肉搭配。
But in the case of cheese you could say, I would recommend pairing this delicious brie
但就奶酪而言，你可以说，我推荐把这种美味的布里
cheese with fruit.
奶酪和水果搭配。
Okay, so you actually have brie with fruit.
好的，所以你真的把布里奶酪和水果一起吃。
That's right.
没错。
It's, well it depends on the kind of cheese.
嗯，这取决于奶酪的种类。
A lot of times you see mozzarella on pizzas, and so it's not paired, it's actually a part
很多时候你会看到马苏里拉奶酪在披萨上，所以它不是搭配，它实际上是
of the dish.
菜肴的一部分。
It's an ingredient, right.
它是一种配料，对吧。
But if you're going to eat a piece of cheese alone, you can have it maybe with some fruit.
但如果你要单独吃一块奶酪，你可以搭配一些水果。
So I guess that's the main difference between pairing and having it as an ingredient.
所以我想这就是搭配和作为配料的主要区别。
It's pairing, you're combining it, but it's not really part of the dish.
搭配是组合在一起，但它不完全是菜肴的一部分。
No, and as an ingredient it's actually, it has to be in the dish to make it work.
不，而作为配料，它实际上必须出现在菜肴中才能发挥作用。
And so you have a lot of these delicious soft cheeses that you eat at breakfast, or sometimes
所以有很多美味的软质奶酪，你早餐吃，或者有时
dessert, ricotta, cream cheese, these are all parts of desserts, like cheesecake for
甜点吃，里科塔奶酪、奶油奶酪，这些都是甜点的一部分，比如芝士蛋糕
example.
就是例子。
Oh yeah, what do they use in cheesecake?
哦，是的，芝士蛋糕里用什么？
Usually cream cheese.
通常是奶油奶酪。
Oh really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
But then you get into these other cheeses which are semi-soft or semi-hard.
但接着你会接触到其他奶酪，这些是半软或半硬的。
And semi here just means part.
这里的“半”只是表示部分的意思。
So it's partially hard, partially soft.
所以它部分是硬的，部分是软的。
And these cheeses are different because you might use them sliced on sandwiches, things
这些奶酪不同，因为你可能会把它们切片用在三明治上，
like that.
诸如此类。
In this category you have American and Colby, and Monterey Jack is also very, very popular.
在这个类别里，有美式奶酪和科尔比奶酪，蒙特雷杰克奶酪也非常非常受欢迎。
So these actually do have a more American sound to it.
所以这些奶酪听起来确实更美式一些。
The American cheese or Monterey Jack, that sounds a little bit different than all the
美式奶酪或蒙特雷杰克奶酪，听起来和我们在软奶酪中提到的那些意大利或法国风味的奶酪有点不同。
Italian or French sounding cheeses that we had in the soft ones.
没错，你甚至会把切达奶酪也归到这个类别里。
That's right, and you'd even have something like cheddar in this category.
There's another...
还有另一种……
Cheddar cheese.
切达奶酪。
Yeah, there's another good cheese.
是的，另一种好奶酪。
As you said, these are very typically put in sandwiches.
就像你说的，这些奶酪通常放在三明治里。
Yeah, I mean you can use them in different ways.
是的，我的意思是你可以用不同的方式吃它们。
Sometimes we grate cheese, that means we rub it against this machine, a grater, to make
有时我们会磨碎奶酪，意思是把它放在一个叫磨碎器的机器上摩擦，
it come out in these little fine pieces.
让它变成细小的碎末。
For example, on top of pasta or on top of nachos.
比如，放在意大利面或玉米片上。
So we have grated cheese, but you can also have sliced cheese, and that's the way that
所以有磨碎的奶酪，但也有切片的奶酪，那是我们切奶酪放在三明治上的方式。
we cut cheese to put it on a sandwich.
所以，比如你去麦当劳买个汉堡，通常汉堡上的奶酪是切达奶酪，对吧？
So for example, if you go to McDonald's and you get a burger, usually the cheese that's
on your hamburger is cheddar cheese, right?
所以，比如你去麦当劳买个汉堡，通常汉堡上的奶酪是切达奶酪，对吧？
That's right, it's a slice of cheddar cheese.
没错，是一片切达奶酪。
Okay.
好的。
So moving on to our next category, well actually towards the end of the different types of
那么进入下一个类别，实际上在软奶酪类别末尾，他们还提到了墨西哥奶酪，比如阿萨德罗奶酪和新鲜奶酪。
cheese under the semi-soft category, they also talk about Mexican cheeses such as asadero
and queso fresco.
那么进入下一个类别，实际上在软奶酪类别末尾，他们还提到了墨西哥奶酪，比如阿萨德罗奶酪和新鲜奶酪。
I love queso fresco.
我喜欢新鲜奶酪。
You've had this before?
你以前吃过吗？
Yes, many times.
是的，很多次了。
What do you usually have it with or how do you pair it?
你通常怎么搭配它吃？
Usually it's an ingredient on tacos because it's a little bit crumbly.
通常是玉米卷的配料，因为它有点易碎。
It's like balls as opposed to being one chunk, one big piece.
它像小球一样，而不是一整块或一大块。
And so we usually have it like that or I've also had it as just a piece of cheese paired
所以我们通常那样吃，或者我也直接把它当一块奶酪，配上炸大蕉或酸奶油。
with a fried plantain or sour cream.
It's actually very good.
其实非常好吃。
The thing with queso fresco is all of the cheese, they also depend on how mature they
新鲜奶酪的问题在于，所有奶酪也取决于它们的成熟度，制作它们花了多长时间。
are, how long they've taken to make them.
And queso fresco means fresh in Spanish and this is the main factor in this type of cheese
而“queso fresco”在西班牙语里是新鲜的意思，这是这种奶酪的主要特点，它非常非常不成熟。
that is very, very immature.
It's a very fresh cheese.
这是一种非常新鲜的奶酪。
You can make it in like a day or two.
你可以在一天或两天内做好。
Exactly.
没错。
It just takes one night to sit and to become cheese basically.
基本上只需要放一夜就能变成奶酪。
But other cheeses, and we'll see some of these in the hard cheeses, take a very long time
但其他奶酪，我们会在硬奶酪中看到一些，需要很长时间才能达到最终的奶酪状态。
to become their final cheese state.
And one of those cheeses is parmesan.
其中一种就是帕玛森奶酪。
In Italy, when you buy parmesan, they have these big wheels of it, they're circles.
在意大利，当你买帕玛森奶酪时，它们是大轮子形状的，是圆形的。
And you have to pay according to how old it is.
你必须根据它的年份来付钱。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
18 months, 36 months.
18个月，36个月。
And it gets more expensive the older it is.
而且越老越贵。
So obviously the older it is, just like wine, it has a more intense flavor.
所以显然越老，就像葡萄酒一样，味道越浓郁。
That's right.
没错。
And there are special characteristics for certain ages.
而且特定年份有特殊的特点。
Sometimes people really like the young ones.
有时人们真的很喜欢年轻的奶酪。
It depends on your taste and what you're going to use it for.
这取决于你的口味和你要用它做什么。
But Romano is another cheese in Italy that's used like parmesan on top of pastas.
但罗马诺奶酪是意大利另一种像帕玛森奶酪一样用在意大利面上的奶酪。
So spaghetti, you would grate it and you put it on top of pasta.
所以意大利面，你会磨碎它，然后放在意大利面上。
What about, they also mentioned this other one, Asiago.
那他们提到的另一种，阿西亚戈奶酪呢？
Asiago cheese, Swiss cheese is the one with the holes.
阿西亚戈奶酪，瑞士奶酪是有洞的那种。
Asiago is, I don't know, maybe it's Spanish.
阿西亚戈奶酪，我不知道，也许是西班牙的。
But then we have Gruyere, which is a French cheese and tends to be very, very, very strong
但还有格鲁耶尔奶酪，这是一种法国奶酪，味道非常非常非常浓烈。
flavored.
And I think Gruyere is the cheese that usually many people use for making fondue.
我认为格鲁耶尔奶酪是很多人用来做奶酪火锅的奶酪。
So they basically have this big pot or this medium-sized pot and all the cheese just melts
所以他们基本上有一个大锅或中号锅，所有奶酪都融化，
and you just dip pieces of bread or vegetables in there and you eat this just melted cheese.
然后你把面包块或蔬菜蘸进去，吃这种融化的奶酪。
Fondue, very popular dish in Switzerland.
奶酪火锅，在瑞士非常受欢迎的菜肴。
That's right.
没错。
But yeah, all these different types of cheese, as you said, there are so many different types
但确实，所有这些不同类型的奶酪，就像你说的，有这么多不同的种类，而且根据年份不同。
and according to the age.
Now you lived in Italy for a while and obviously they are a nation that enjoy having wine and
你在意大利住过一段时间，显然他们是一个经常享用葡萄酒和奶酪的国家，对吧？
cheese very regularly, right?
That's right.
没错。
And I have to say that people in Parma take their cheese very, very seriously.
我不得不说，帕尔马的人对他们的奶酪非常非常认真。
How serious?
有多认真？
Well, a lot of people buy these big pieces of parmesan cheese and they keep them in the
嗯，很多人会买大块的帕玛森奶酪，放在冰箱里，
refrigerator and you don't just put the parmesan cheese on the spaghetti.
而且你不会只是把帕玛森奶酪撒在意大利面上。
You also break pieces of it and you eat it alone with a glass of wine or some people
你还会掰下小块，单独配一杯葡萄酒吃，或者有些人……
like to put a little drop of balsamic vinegar on top of the cheese to give it some flavor.
喜欢在奶酪上滴一点香醋来增添风味。
So there are many different ways to eat it.
所以有很多不同的吃法。
I'm sure it's different all over the country, but mozzarella, parmesan cheese, Romano, these
我敢肯定全国各地的吃法都不一样，但马苏里拉奶酪、帕尔马干酪、罗马诺干酪，这些
are all cheeses that are very, very important in Italian culture.
都是在意大利文化中非常重要的奶酪。
It's very interesting because, well, obviously we have listeners from all over the world,
这很有趣，因为，嗯，显然我们有来自世界各地的听众，
but some countries have a good culture for wine, cheese and cured meats.
但有些国家有很好的葡萄酒、奶酪和腌肉文化。
Like for example, in South America, if you visit Argentina or Chile, they are a nation
比如，在南美洲，如果你去阿根廷或智利，他们是一个
that actually have a lot of variety of cheese, wines and cured meats.
实际上有很多种类奶酪、葡萄酒和腌肉的国家。
But if you take a trip to maybe Colombia, they're not really that type of culture.
但如果你去哥伦比亚，他们就不是那种文化。
They really consume cheese and wine in the same manner.
他们吃奶酪和喝葡萄酒的方式差不多。
Interesting.
有意思。
I wonder if it has to do with the historical relationship between Europe and the place
我想知道这是否与欧洲和像阿根廷这样的地方之间的历史关系有关。
like Argentina.
像阿根廷。
In Argentina, there's lots of Italian former people who came over from Italy many, many
在阿根廷，有很多意大利裔的人，他们很多很多年前从意大利移民过来。
years ago.
年前。
So that might have something to do with it.
所以这可能与此有关。
Spain has a very strong tradition of cured meats and cheeses.
西班牙有非常悠久的腌肉和奶酪传统。
They have manchego cheese, things like this.
他们有曼彻格奶酪之类的东西。
So I wonder if there's a relationship there.
所以我想知道它们之间是否有联系。
I think it's definitely an influence in some way.
我认为这肯定在某种程度上是一种影响。
But the thing with cheese, I think in many places it's very expensive.
但关于奶酪，我觉得在很多地方它都很贵。
It can be.
可能是这样。
Comparatively to if you can have a regular mozzarella cheese, but sometimes these other
相比之下，如果你能买到普通的马苏里拉奶酪，但有时这些其他
types, they can be very expensive.
种类，它们可能非常贵。
Yeah, it's like good wine.
是啊，就像好酒一样。
If you really want to pay for good cheese, it's going to cost you a lot of money.
如果你真想买好奶酪，那得花很多钱。
Now what about this famous blue cheese?
那这种著名的蓝纹奶酪呢？
We didn't mention it, but this is a very famous French cheese that basically has mold on it.
我们之前没提到，但这是一种非常著名的法国奶酪，基本上上面有霉菌。
Well, yeah, all cheese, you're growing cultures.
嗯，是啊，所有奶酪都是在培养菌种。
You're growing these things that are alive.
你在培养这些活的东西。
But blue cheese, you can actually see it.
但蓝纹奶酪，你实际上能看到它。
And it's moldy.
而且它发霉了。
It's white and there's some blue or green mold.
它是白色的，还有一些蓝色或绿色的霉菌。
And some people love it and some people hate it.
有些人喜欢，有些人讨厌。
I think it depends on your tastes, but it does have a very strong flavor.
我觉得这取决于个人口味，但它确实味道很浓。
Do you personally like it or dislike it?
你个人是喜欢还是不喜欢？
I do not like blue cheese, but I love other kinds of cheeses like camembert, which is
我不喜欢蓝纹奶酪，但我喜欢其他种类的奶酪，比如卡门贝尔奶酪，这是一种
a French cheese with a very strong flavor, very stinky cheese.
味道很浓的法国奶酪，很臭的奶酪。
So it's not necessarily that it's strong.
所以不一定是因为味道浓。
It's just that I don't like the taste very much.
只是我不太喜欢那个味道。
Okay.
好吧。
Actually, it's very popular to put on salads, right?
实际上，它很流行放在沙拉上，对吧？
Blue cheese sauce or a dressing.
蓝纹奶酪酱或调味汁。
Blue cheese dressing, yeah, that's right.
蓝纹奶酪调味汁，是的，没错。
It's made out of blue cheese.
它是用蓝纹奶酪做的。
It's a very interesting topic and I'm sure that locally, many people also make or countries
这是一个非常有趣的话题，我敢肯定在当地，很多人也制作，或者各个国家
have their own types of cheese.
都有自己的奶酪种类。
I know for example, in Ecuador, we do have also something very similar to queso fresco
我知道，比如在厄瓜多尔，我们也有一种非常类似于新鲜奶酪的东西，
that's commonly used for breakfast.
通常用于早餐。
And here's an interesting thing.
这里有个有趣的事。
They put it in their cup of coffee.
他们把它放进咖啡杯里。
No way.
不会吧。
It's cheese cheese, isn't it?
那是奶酪，对吧？
It's cheese.
是奶酪。
So basically you have coffee with milk, very popular in Latin America.
所以基本上你喝加牛奶的咖啡，这在拉丁美洲很流行。
And people will take a piece of cheese and put it in their coffee.
人们会拿一块奶酪放进咖啡里。
So obviously with the heat, it won't melt completely, but it will become very bendy
显然，因为热度，它不会完全融化，但会变得非常有弹性
and very soft.
而且很软。
And then they'll have it with the coffee and the bread.
然后他们和咖啡、面包一起吃。
So it gives it a very interesting taste.
所以这给了它一种非常有趣的味道。
It may sound a little bit peculiar, but it actually has a very, very interesting taste,
这听起来可能有点奇怪，但实际上它有一种非常非常有趣的味道，
very good taste.
非常好的味道。
I've had many friends try and they're like, wow, you wouldn't really think that you would
我有很多朋友试过，他们都说，哇，你真不会想到
probably dip cheese in coffee, but it works.
会把奶酪蘸咖啡吃，但确实行得通。
No, it's a very unusual combination.
不，这是一个非常不寻常的组合。
Now what is this special cheese called?
那这种特殊的奶酪叫什么？
It's called queso de mesa, which is basically a normal, common, everyday table cheese.
它叫餐桌奶酪，基本上就是一种普通、常见、日常的餐桌奶酪。
So it's not any particular, it's very similar to queso fresco, very immature cheese.
所以它不是特别的，非常类似于新鲜奶酪，是一种很嫩的奶酪。
So I'm very curious to know if in your country you also have a strong cheese culture.
所以我很好奇，在你的国家是否也有浓厚的奶酪文化。
And if in your country you guys do have a lot of cheese, what kind of cheese is it?
如果在你的国家你们有很多奶酪，那是什么种类的奶酪？
I know that every country has its own variety of cheeses and some places like China aren't
我知道每个国家都有自己的奶酪品种，有些地方比如中国并不
really into cheese.
太喜欢奶酪。
So you can let us know if your country doesn't really have that many cheese options.
所以你可以告诉我们，如果你的国家没有那么多奶酪选择。
So we're very curious to hear about you and your taste in cheese.
所以我们很想知道你和你的奶酪口味。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
See you later.
再见。
Enjoy your meal.
请享用你的美食。